no no i'm always open to talk to anyone how are you doing israel like the country oh nice shocker
can we can ask you a few questions with the disclaimer that i don't speak for anyone
besides myself and i'm not the expert on everything you can ask for everyone what
so what brings you out today i live here you live here but what's your position on
so i do the bars not everyone uses a chicken i personally use cash so i do the practice but i
don't use a chicken like i would say the average dude so why is it that you still have people
practicing by murdering chickens rather than just using change if it's the same thing using using
money if it's the same thing so i would say the average dude does use money just out of convenience
or sanitary whatever it is if you're entering a pacific community there is an overall vibe of
being more like traditional this is what my parents did what my grandparents did so they're more intent
i'm using chicken but the chicken also has twofold added elements one is i understand that you're
probably vegan and that's fine i support that lifestyle but if these animals are basically being
prepped for the holiday because there is elevated consumption around the holiday obviously more
grocery shopping and everything else so the idea of comparus is hey these chickens are being slaughtered
for the holiday whether you agree with that or not that's fine but you should be part of the process
because we're going into this holiday where we talk about mortality how life is finite consequences of
one's actions etc so be part of that process to understand life is delicate life is valued life is
precious and if you're going to be processing chickens for the holiday you should be very conscientious of
what that process entails it sort of puts you in a mentality that we would consider appropriate to go into
a holiday like yom kippur there's also another practice for example to visit a cemetery at these
times there's a cemetery of people you look up to people you are related to because it puts you in a
mindset of life ends at a certain point what i do matters what i do has an impact the other process of
this chicken practice specifically is that we try to do whatever kindness we can before a holiday
like yom kippur to build up whatever minute merits we can so these chickens if they're being slaughtered
kosher as you see they go towards people that can't afford food for the holiday we may not agree on
the actual consumption of animal products and that's fine you do you but the thought process is hey let's
go do something good so all these people come here they buy the chicken it gets slaughtered in a kosher
way and it goes towards people who can't afford food for the holiday so you go into yom kippur you're
like hey i'm aware of mortality i'm aware of how life is finite and also i try to help out the
poor in my community and that's the idea personally i use cash but and then that cash goes towards
charity but you could use the chicken as well setting veganism aside because that's a 21st century
term i actually speak from the position of the torah as well from the tanakh and this this isn't in the
Torah or the Tanakh no it's not this is not a direct amendment from god this is something developed i
don't want to give the exact date because i'm not the expert but like i said it's a mentality of
hey how can we get into the spirit of the holiday so we want charity we want to be in touch with
mortality so this developed a lot of what we do is not a direct one of the 613 commandments because
actually today's day and age a lot of those commandments do depend on having the temple
so some of the things basically the 613 are divided into positives and negatives a lot of those
positives and negatives do revolve around you can only do them in the land of israel for example
you can only do in the temple verse so and there are derivative commandments as well
well i've asked a lot of people this here and i can't seem to get an answer you're doing street
interviews you're going to run into some writer some list right but how do you swear the prophets
like yeshua who all say that god didn't desire sacrifice he wants chesed mercy you mentioned
mercy mercy or loving kindness sure yeah that literally we god wants that not sacrifice
not sacrifice yes sacrifice why i assume you're coming from a christian perspective right uh i consider
myself okay so is that you're gonna have to break that down for me well jesus following yeah yeah yeah
yeshua is fair enough so why did yeshua never ban slavery all the things he spoke about never said
slavery is bad not once that's something i grapple with well he in his uh in his walk with the
stories of the samaritan stories like um hero israel the lord your god is one love your neighbor as
yourself sure sure that's not conducive to slavery what about your neighbor's slave but it's he overturned
what those traditions meant he he actually rebuked the pharisees for their traditions about slavery
slavery well slavery falls into that it's in the it's in the 613 laws that's derivative the 613 laws
are how you have to treat your slave more than you to do it i mean if you want to bring the hebrew i
encourage you to look this up yeah we should kind of it kind of rabo meaning anyone who buys
themselves a slave just got themselves a master because the way you have to treat your slave puts
you beneath your slave that's the jewish principle behind it jesus never said hey we got the nazarenes
kept no slaves it's a historical fact also we skipped over the question you asked about how do you
reconcile hosea jeremiah and uh yes the other prophets jeremiah 7 22 says god did not command
sacrifices he didn't command oh this isn't a sacrifice then what is this like i said before i'm sorry i
i feel like this might be a super important point of it this is not a slaughter sacrifice to peas god in
any way this is hey these chickens are being produced for the holiday because people buy more chicken
around the holiday as a community we're bringing that out of the warehouses that i'm sure you're very
against that i'm largely against as well and we bring it into the community so that you should be aware
of what finality and mortality looks like so why not it should invoke a sensitivity so if it's about kindness
and coming up to mortality it's not what you just said that's what it's about it's not about kindness
you brought up kindness over there yeah separate points you mentioned that that was before i mentioned
has said i only brought up has said because you said this is not it's not a sacrifice this is saying
hey this is the standard so it goes in the tone for sin no this is not bring it into you when we we're
atoning for our sins tomorrow that's the big day when you go into the big day to atone for sins you're saying hey i just
did this process i know what the end of what the end of life looks like it's super sensitive it's super
delicate i'm in a headset or in a mindset headspace why don't we why do we need to murder a being to
know what the end of life is like we're not murdering a being we hold the chicken we hold the chicken and
there's a prayer then we give it towards the people who are actually part of the standard kosher meat
production and we're supposed to visualize it we're supposed to see it is ending no one here is
slaughtering their own chickens everyone here is holding their chicken but the shokhet is the
shokhet is part of standard meat production for the holiday right there's elevated consumerism around
things how is slitting the floor not murder no that's standard meat production this always is if you want
to talk about meat murder there's two conversations there's meat is murder and kapharos kapharos is a
practice and meat is murder as another conversation the murder part the swinging of the chicken over
the head is not for atonement it's not to to absolve sin no the swinging of the chicken is saying
hey i mean look at the text online it says this chicken is going towards feeding the needy and the
charity and i'm going into yom kippur where i'm going to pray for the it's not a sacrifice at all
saying hey this chicken is going towards soup kitchens so what does the swinging do
it's a symbolic way of connecting you to the chicken saying hey this is going to a soup chicken
this is going towards a soup kitchen and i'm going towards yom kippur and i'm going to pray
so i'm taking part in charity and feeding the needy before i go into this holy day
so i got some sort of merit to pull on that's the idea well it's odd because i've talked to so
many practitioners who say it's for the uh absolution of sin for the atonement of sin
no but they say that they're trying to get rid of their sin before the day of the church so it's
pre-yom kippur that is the day of atoning for sins so it's sort of like lumped into one process
that's a b a lot of the people here english is not their first language and there may be a lumping in
three you might speak some people who are not so intelligent on the street that's definitely an option
as well but most importantly this concept of saying like oh i put my sins on this chicken and now
i don't have to worry about anything that's christianity we don't do that at least we use
the chicken they use a man but we say hey this chicken is going towards the soup kitchen it's
feeding the needy i'm going to go towards and atone for my sins we don't do the christian practice of
my sins are on that guy who died for me and now i don't have to worry about it we're about to go into
a 25-hour pass we're going to pray and talk for our sins and by the way i don't we we don't we don't
do sin transference if that's what you're asking so then what about all the levitical laws where the
blood brings the sin of the altar and the blood atones for sin no that was a visual thing you would
come in and you would sponsor let's say whatever cattle or livestock it was in the temple the priests
or in this case the shoket who would be who would be uh that's what i'm looking for like the whole
production of the animal meal practice as it is and you're supposed to stand by on watch because you're
supposed to understand how valuable and how precious life is and the idea is that when you leave the
temple you're going to lead a little bit of a better life because do the kids watch what over here
here or at the temple temple i would i wouldn't know because i wasn't there okay but here i imagine
most kids probably do not watch why do you think that is the same reason you wouldn't take them to
anything process the same reason you wouldn't take your kids to success there's a certain there's a
certain graphicness that we try to shield child instincts and the same reason i wouldn't take my
kids to the sweatshop the same reason i wouldn't take them to an iphone production factory maybe because
it's just what iphone production well any type of exploitation i think any exploitation isn't great
the question is what do you lump into exploitation i think everything is exploitation you shoot sony
sony's exploiting their production life i shoot an icon icon's exploiting someone someone's mining
cobalt for your memory cards but but you're missing a key point you can make sony cameras and you can
make iphones and technology without exploitation it's possible you wouldn't buy it it's going to be 20 grand
for that camera but what i'm saying is it's possible it is impossible to murder an animal
without exploiting it it's impossible it's inherent it's not it's it's effectively impossible no but
it's it's if cameras quadrupled in price sony would go bankrupt they're going to say if you pitch it
to sony this is all logical fallacy no if you pitch technology technology can be technology in and of
itself is not inherently exploitative it can be made without exploitation no it can be made without it
if i pitch to sony hey every production step of your your a735 has to be paid you're running from the
questions i'm coming i'll get back to the question i'm just going to finish this one point and then
you're running and then we get back to it if i told sony hey everyone on your production line
needs a living wage from mine to bnh yeah they would look at you and say well that's impossible
yeah but you're you're also confining that to the current world we live in there's a possible world
where the gdp and the government and and things operate in such a way that we don't have to pay
so much money for devices that could be but it's utopia but that's regardless the argument is it's
possible to make technology without exploitation it is impossible to kill and to murder a living
being without exploitation it's impossible i don't want to be accused of running for the questions so
i want to make sure i'm addressing it what was the last point